Preliminary Guide to the Neal E. Miller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - East Rock Neighborhood Association 1956 (Box 17)
  - Fluoridation, Resolution on [and NEM's letters to Mayor Richard Lee, etc.], 1955-1956 (Box 17)
  - NEM - Peace - 1970 [re Vietnam war] (Box 17)
  - NEM - Garden [Chestnut trees, etc.], 1970-1978 (Box 17)
  - "Primate" film 1974 (Box 17)
  - Research Funding [NEM letters re] 1977 (Box 17)
  - APA 1975 - Gold Medal [Award] to NEM (Box 17)
  - USPH Grant #MH-647 (1952-1969) "Behavioral Laws of Motivation and Conflict" + Progress Reports, MH 647 1953-1965 (Box 17)
  - USPH Grant #MY-2949 (1959-1963) "Analysis of Drug Effects on Fear and Conflict" (Box 17)
  - USPH - NIMH project reports 1965 [summary of work under grants 647 and 2949] (Box 17)
  - USPH Grant #MH-13189 (1966 -1975) "Mechanisms of Motivation, Learning and Development" [combining MH 647 and MY 2949] (Box 17)
  - USPH Grant #MH-19183 (1970-1973) "Therapeutic Training of Autonomic Functions" (Box 18)
  - USPH Grant #MH-26920 (1975-1977) "Mechanisms of Motivation, Learning and Development" [replacing MH 13189] (Box 18)
  - USPH Grant #MH-28145 (1975-1979) "Posture Training Device for Idiopathic Scoliosis" (Box 18)
  - Grant HL [Natl. Heart, Lung Inst.] 21532 (1977-1981) - "Cardiovascular Homeostasis and Learning" (Box 18)
  - BRSG-Reynolds [Biomedical Research Support Grant], 1981-1983 (Box 18)
  - Grant Foundation 1973-1975 "Brian Mechanisms of Motivation and Stress" [material on cells firing for fear] (Box 18)
  - Hoffman-La Roche, Inc. Grant [uncommitted, for several studies], 1973-1976 (Box 18)
  - MacArthur Foundation Grant 81-157 -"Variables Controlling Visceral Learning", 1981-1983 (Box 18)
  - March of Dimes Grant # 6-137 [for lab equipment], 1977-1979 (Box 18)
  - NAMH [National Association for Mental Health] Grants, 1969-1974 (Box 18)
  - Grant HL [National Heart, Lung Institute] 34205 (1984-1985) - "Cardiovascular Homeostasis and Learning" (Box 18)
  - Nutrition Foundation Grant #390 [3 projects], 1968 (Box 18)
  - Philip Morris Grant [nicotinic synapses in the hippocampus], 1972 (Box 18)
  - Renfield Foundation Grant [incl. letter on "Mysteries of the Mind" television program, Jan 1980], 1977 (Box 18)
  - Rockefeller U. Grant for Research in Reproductive Biology [Bruce McEwen], 1970 (Box 18)
  - Sloan Foundation Grant - "Interdisciplinary Research in the Neurosciences", 1976 (Box 18)
  - Spencer Foundation Grant - "'Biofeedback': The Voluntary Control of Autonomic Processes", 1973 (Box 18)
  - Mexico City - IX Congress Neurophysiology [Symposium], 1961 (Box 19)
  - British Psychological Society, 1963 (Box 19)
  - Texas, U. of - Symposium and Book on Personality Change, 1964 (Box 19)
  - Learning Visceral Responses - Rockefeller U. Colloquium, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Lecture in Moscow - 18th International Congress of Psychology, 1966 (Box 19)
  - Invitations - Talks, Colloquia, Writing, etc. June 1966 to '67 (Box 19)
  - Learning and Reinforcement Symposium - Einstein College of Medicine, 1967 (Box 19)
  - Princeton Conference on Punishment - June 1967 (Box 19)
  - Pavlovian Conference - Nov. 1967 (Box 19)
  - [U-NC at] Chapel Hill - Nov. 1967 (Box 19)
  - NRP [Neurosciences Research Program] - Consolidation of Memory Trace" - Nov. 1967 (Box 19)
  - Lab Visit Talk - 1/10/68, 1968 (Box 19)
  - "Objective Indicators of Psychopathology" - NEM chmn. of Biometrics Research Workshop - Feb. '68, 1968 (Box 19)
  - "Fear and Courage" - Talk at Emma Willard School, 5/23/68, 1968 (Box 19)
  - Society for Psychophysiological Research symposium talk - October 1968 (Box 19)
  - Langfeld Lectures [series of 6 lectures at Princeton, Nov.-Dec. 1968] (Box 19)
  - [Kenneth] Spence Memorial Lecture, Psychonomic Society, Oct. 11, 1968 (Box 19)
  - "Hullian Impact on Psychology" - Talk at APA, 8/27/69, 1969 (Box 19)
  - U. New Mexico [Talk - 5/23/69], 1969 (Box 19)
  - [Lecture at] XIX International Congress of Psychology, London - "Autonomic Learning: Clinical and Physiological Implications" Jul-Aug '69, 1969 (Box 19)
  - [Talk at] UCLA 50th Anniversary ["Glands, Emotions, and Learning"], 5/19-24/1969 (Box 19)
  - Harvard U. [Colloquium] 5/8/69, 1969 (Box 19)
  - U. Penn. [Colloquium] 4/23/69, 1969 (Box 19)
  - "From the Brain to Behavior" - NEM Invited Lecture at XII Interamerican Congress of Psychology, Uruguay, March-April,1969 (Box 19)
  - NYU Medical Center talk, Dec. 1969 (Box 19)
  - NY Neural Society talk, Nov. 1969 (Box 19)
  - UC-San Francisco Medical Center talk, Oct. 1969 (Box 19)
  - NY Medical College talk, Sept. 1969 (Box 19)
  - Council for High B.P. Research talk, Oct. 1969 (Box 19)
  - American Gastroenterological Association talk, May 1970 (Box 19)
  - Temple University - American Philosophical Society talk, April 1971 (Box 19)
  - American Psychosomatic Society Workshop, Washington, DC, 23/20/70, 1970 (Box 19)
  - WNBC-TV Research Project [on visceral learning], 1970 (Box 19)
  - Puerto Rico [University - public lecture ] Feb., 1970 (Box 19)
  - American College of Physicians - NY regional meeting, talk on "Learning of Visceral and Glandular Responses," Jan. 1970 (Box 19)
  - Australia, 1970 (Box 19)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association, Dec., 1971 (Box 19)
  - NY G-E [Gastroenterological] Association talk, NYC, 1971 (Box 19)
  - Salmon Lecture [NY Academy of Medicine, Salmon Committee on Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene], Nov., 1971 (Box 19)
  - Stresa [Italy - location of discussion session on a psychologist's perspective on cardiovascular disease], July, 1971 (Box 19)
  - NIMH - 25th Anniversary [of Mental Health Act] - NEM on "Some Psychosomatic Effects of Learning", 1971 (Box 19)
  - DuPont correspondence [NEM leaving for 14-day speaking tour in Poland, Sweden, and Denmark, Feb. 1971] (Box 19)
  - Brazil [Symposium on Psychopharmacology, NEM speaking on "Chemical coding of hunger and thirst in the brain"] - May 1971 (Box 19)
  - AIMS [American Institute for Mental Studies [NEM part of advisory group], April 1971 (Box 19)
  - Sweden, 1971 [NEM lectures at U. of Stockholm and Uppsala U.] (Box 19)
  - Mexico, 1974 [NEM's Ms. "Psychosomatic Effects of Learning' for book to be published on the 4th Symposium on Behavior Modification, held in Mexico in Jan. 1974] (Box 19)
  - Annual Review of Psychology, May 1977 [NEM's chapter, "Biofeedback and Visceral Learning"] (Box 19)
  - Lectures - Tallahassee [Florida State U. - a series, "Bridges between the Laboratory and the Clinic: Lessons from a Persoal History of Research"], 1984 (Box 19)
  - "Psychobiography of a Scientist" [Invited lecture at APA annual meeting, August 1992 [Rest of talks and lectures are in the current file cabinets under "Miller"] (Box 19)
  - USPH: Film, Rough Draft of - Jan. 1956 [on "Motivation of Learning by Electrical Stimulation of the Brain," funded by Grant #M-647] (Box 20)
  - [More experiments:] Brown, J. S. - Spatial Gradients of Approach and Avoidance, 1939 (Box 20)
  - Brown, Judson S. - Conflict, Approach-Avoidance Function of Strength of Drive and Strength of Punishment, 1939 (Box 20)
  - Murray - Bursary exp.[eriment] - Generalization of Extinction "Barrier", 1950 (Box 20)
  - Morton Experiment, 1937 (Box 20)
  - Myers Experiment: Acquisition data, Winter 1948 (Box 20)
  - Myers Experiment: Testing day data, Winter 1948, Spring 1949 (Box 20)
  - Myers - Approach as a function of number of reinforcements and subsequent shock (Box 20)
  - Porter, L.W. - Exploratory [experiment] - Alcohol addiction in cats, 1954 (Box 20)
  - Porter, L.W., and Coons, E.E., Alcohol, fear reduction [experiment] - Summer 1954 (Box 20)
  - Richter, Melissa - Radioactive isotope injected into 3rd ventricle of cats; rate of dispersion, 1954 (Box 20)
  - Richter, M. - Ventricular Injections: Histology - Summer 1955 (Box 20)
  - Sachs and Kohn - Reliability of Shock Threshold (Box 20)
  - Sheffield, Virginia - Acquired Drive (black-white compartments), 1942 (Box 20)
  - Sheffield, V. - Anxiety Experiments: Acquired Drive(black-white compartments), 1942 (Box 20)
  - Michel, Libby - Stress - Learning to Resist Pain and Fear [Experiment Summer 1958] (Box 20)
  - Regrets, 1966-1967 [NEM couldn't attend meetings, etc.] (Box 20)
  - Regrets, 1970-1971 (Box 20)
  - C.V. and Bibliography [NEM, through 1983] (Box 20)
  - NEM: Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, 1961-1984 (Box 20)
  - Rockefeller U. Correspondence, 1966-1980 (Box 20)
  - Talks [NEM], 1953-1956 (Box 20)
  - Talks that were taken to Chile - Conflict, motivation, etc., 1953-1963 (Box 20)
  - Rockefeller University Training Grant Application, 1974-1983 (Box 20)
  - R.U. Personnel and Finances, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Animal House [satellite lab animal facility]1977-1981 (Box 20)
  - Animal Research Committee [Rockefeller U.], 1985 (Box 20)
  - Safety [site visits to Rockefeller lab], 1985 (Box 20)
  - Space [Office at R.U.], 1971 (Box 20)
  - Plans of Space, 5/18/66 [office at R.U.], 1966 (Box 20)
  - Flexner Colloquy, 1979 (Box 20)
  - Hartline Committee [on Neurophysiology, R.U.], 1971 (Box 20)
  - R.U. Exec. Committee, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Seitz, Frederick [President of R.U after Detlev Bronk. - correspondence w. NEM], 1968 (Box 20)
  - Lederberg [Joshua - R.U. President after Seitz - correspondence w. NEM], 1978-1981 (Box 20)
  - R.U. - Noise Study, 1982 (Box 20)
  - Young, Richard [correspondence re major accomplishments in NEM's lab in 1970s], 1979 (Box 20)
  - R.U. Senate, 1969-1981 (Box 20)
  - Faculty Committee, R.U. [1967-1970] (Box 20)
  - [Rockefeller University] MD-PhD Program Committee, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Medicine - Reading List, 1980 (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Science [Faculty meetings] 1980-1981 (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Science [Faculty meetings] 1979 (Box 21)
  - Neuroscience Programs at R.U., 1976 (Box 21)
  - Nichols, Rodney [Exec. V.P. of R.U.], 1971-1980 (Box 21)
  - Scientific Advisory Committee, R.U., 1972 (Box 21)
  - Student Budgets, R.U, 1969-1976 (Box 21)
  - Research Plans, 1965-1966 [Students'] (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller University Committee for Behavioral Sciences, 1967-1978 (Box 21)
  - R.U. Students in Behavioral Sciences, 1967-1973 (Box 21)
  - Learning and Memory Seminar 1974-1975 (Box 21)
  - Learning and Memory Seminar 11973-1974 (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Sciences [Faculty meetings] 1980-1981 (Box 21)
  - R.U. Behavioral Sciences - Description (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Science Courses, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Learning and Motivation, Fall 1971 (Box 21)
  - EM - Behavioral Fungibility - Behavioral Sci. Discussion Group 10/23/69, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Conditioning - Classical, Operant [handwritten notes] (Box 21)
  - Lab Course:Experimental Psych, Spring 1969 (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Sci. Discussion Group: Sessions on Aggression, 1968-1969 (Box 21)
  - Orientation - Motivation and Learning, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller University Orientation Lectures, 1967 - 1) Motivation; 2) Learning (Box 21)
  - Miller - Motivation (Outline of possible lecture or workshop session) (Box 21)
  - Behavioral Sci. Reading Lists (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller University Seminar (Biological Basis of Learning), 1966 (Box 21)
  - Visiting Seminars, 1967 (Box 21)
  - Report of [R.U.] President, 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Kappas Report, April 1976 [NIH site visit to Rockefeller University] (Box 21)
  - Annual Reports, 1968-1978 (Box 21)
  - Catalog Listing: Rockefeller University 1966 (Box 21)
  - Azmitia, Efrain C., 1973 (Box 21)
  - Conrad, Lily, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Drewnowski, Adam, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Fields, Craig, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Forman, David, 1978 (Box 21)
  - Giulian, Dana, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Gray, Peter, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Larkin, Ron, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Mackel, Robert, 1978 (Box 21)
  - O'Neil, Patrick, 1968 (Box 21)
  - Rubin, Lee, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Zigmond, Richard, 1975 (Box 21)
  - American Psychologist on Behavioral Medicine, 1982 (Box 22)
  - APA 1984 - American Psychologist Master, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Anxiety Conference, NIH, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Barchas, Jack, M.D., 1983 (Box 22)
  - Behavioral Medicine [Paper] for Science, 1971 (Box 22)
  - Behavioral Medicine Update [commentary for SBM mag], 1979 (Box 22)
  - "Behavior and Health" - for Five-Year Outlook for Science and Technology, 1981 (Box 22)
  - BSA [Biofeedback Society of America] 1985 - [NEM Presidential Address] (Box 22)
  - Budapest Talk [published in Russian Journal of Higher Neurological Function], 1981 (Box 22)
  - Chapter I [Conflict Behavior] (Box 22)
  - Davis and Miller - A technique for mixing the blood of unanesthetized rats. Journal of Applied Physiology., 1966 (Box 22)
  - Miller - Instrumental conditioning of visceral responses [correspondence with William Estes, editor, JCPP ], 1966 (Box 22)
  - Behavioral Medicine [Conference at] Yale, 2/4/77, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Coile and NEM - American Psychologist article, June 1984 (Box 22)
  - Corsini [NEM article on "Behavioral Medicine" in Wiley Encyclopedia of Psychology, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Dollard (John) obit. [written by NEM for American Psychologist ], 1982 (Box 22)
  - On Dollard [a short bio written on John Dollard for the International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences ]; includes correspondence with Dollard], 1978 (Box 22)
  - Foreword [by NEM] for Birbaumer Book [ Behavioral Medicine, by Miltner, Birbaumer, and Gerber], 1984 (Box 22)
  - Foreword [by NEM] for Goldstein Book [Reporting Science The Case of Aggression, ed. Jeffrey Goldstein], 1984 (Box 22)
  - Foreword [by NEM] to IAH [Institute for Advancement of Health] book, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Immune Response Collaboration [ Science article, series of talks], 1981 (Box 22)
  - "International Review of Applied Psychology" [Eng. version of "Revue Internationale de Psychologie Appliquee", correspondence from J. Matarazzo on special issue on Behavioral Medicine - NEM one of guest editors], 1981 (Box 22)
  - Judson Brown chapter [project honoring J. Brown, NEM's first research asst. and Ph.D. student on his retirement], 1979 (Box 22)
  - Landis et al. - [Paper on] Diabetes (Box 22)
  - Miles, Walter [including obituaries NEM wrote for his mentor, printed in Yearbook of American Philosophical Society and American Psychologist, with correspondence with Dr. Miles' daughter], 1979 (Box 22)
  - NATO, Greece 6/30-7/1/81 [Symposium on Behavioral Medicine- NEM spoke on "Potentialities of Automation and of Continuous Recording in Life", 1981 (Box 22)
  - NCI - Behavioral Biology [National Cancer Institute, Behavioral Medicine Branch - NEM wrote chapter on behavioral factors rel. to cancer for book Biological Mediators... ], 1981 (Box 22)
  - NEM #203- "Behavioral Med, Biofeedback, and Homeostasis," in Psychiatric Annals, 1981 (Box 22)
  - NEM #204 - 1981 [NEM article #204 in Bibliography, chapter in Perspectives on Behavioral Medicine: 1980, ed. S. Weiss] (Box 22)
  - Behavioral Medicine Ms. [Various mss. and talks, from '73 on, incl. NEM #220, paper for Annual Review of Psychology '83], 1973 (Box 22)
  - Pavlovian Society, Moscow 1984 [NEM paper presented, pub. later in Pavlovian Journal ] (Box 22)
  - Placebo Symposium? [NEM did write article on placebo effects], 1982 (Box 22)
  - Preface to Ray book,Evaluation of ClinicalBiofeedback, 1981 (Box 22)
  - NEM #229 - "Value and Ethics of Research on Animals" [APA talk and article - NEM's presentation was picketed by PETA and name slandered], 1984 (Box 22)
  - Zimbardo "Prologue" [NEM #230 - Prologue to Psychology and Life, ed. P. Zimbardo - on animal research], 1985 (Box 22)
  - Psychol. Medicine 9/83 [NEM editorial for British journal Psychological Medicine ], 1983 (Box 22)
  - Psychology Today '84 [Interview with NEMwhich became article, " RX: Biofeedback", #, printed in magazine, then reprinted in Ginn Press in 1985], 1984 (Box 22)
  - Psychology Today '82 - [NEM's "Brain Research and Behavioral Medicine" for journal's 15th anniversary], 1982 (Box 22)
  - Psychology 10 Yr. from Now [invited message for new textbook, People - The Humanistic Science of Psychology], 1977 (Box 22)
  - Scott, Foresman Text Series 1985 (Box 22)
  - Purdue, 3/19/82 (also Brit. Psychological Society 4/4/82) [NEM talk, "Behavioral Medicine"] (Box 22)
  - Scoliosis Ms. - PNAS 12/4/84 ["Behavioral method for the treatment of idiopathic scoliosis", by Dworkin, Miller, etc., pub. in Proceedings from National Academy of Sciences, 1985], 1984 (Box 22)
  - Scoliosis [ms.] #2 ["Biofeedback in the Treatment of Scoliosis and Kyphosis," by Cevy, Birbaumer, Dworkin, NEM, et al., pub. in Clinical Orthopaedics and Related Research ], 1985 (Box 22)
  - Soviet Exchange '82 - Report [on biobehavioral approaches to treatment and prevention of hypertension - NEM and S. Weiss to Russia], 1982 (Box 22)
  - "Understanding Science" [NEM talk - in Russia?] (Box 22)
  - U.S.-USSR Symposium on Hypertension, 1982 (Box 22)
  - APA 1983 - Value and Ethics of Research on Animals" [talk at APA convention, 1983] (Box 23)
  - Annual Review of Psychology '83 [NEM article #220, on Biofeedback and Visceral Learning], 1983 (Box 23)
  - NEM Ms. - "Value of Behavioral Research on Animals", #233, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Miller - Basmajian chapter [ NEM #245, chapter in Biofeedback: Principles and Practice..., ed. JohnV. Basmajian], 1989 (Box 23)
  - NEM Ms. #250 - "How the Brain Affects the Health of the Body", 1990 (Box 23)
  - NEM Ms #255 - "Behavior to the Brain to Health" - early drafts (Autobiography), 1990 (Box 23)
  - NEM Ms #255 - "Behavior to the Brain to Health" - in Paths of Discovery, 1992 (Box 23)
  - NEM Ms. #256 - "Some Examples of Psychophysiology and the Unconscious" [in Biofeedback and Self Regulation ], 1992 (Box 23)
  - Handbook of Behavioral Health, 1981-1984 [Matarazzo, Miller, et al., eds.] (Box 23)
  - Miller for Kasschau [ed. of intro psych book - NEM chapter on research and applications], 1984 (Box 23)
  - Gentry Ms. [NEM chapter "Behavioral Medicine: An Introductory Perspective", for ], 1984 (Box 23)
  - Leipzig Ms [Publication of Proceedings of Leipzig Symposium on Biofeedback, 1980 - NEM and Elissabeth Richter-Heinrich, eds.]., 1981 (Box 23)
  - NY Academy Sci. 4/29/82 [NEM talk on ethics of animal research - basis for article in Psychology Today the following year ], 1982 (Box 23)
  - Talks on Fear - 1950, '51, '52, '61 (Box 23)
  - Other Talks - 1951, '53,,54, '55, '57, '58 (Box 23)
  - Talks - 1960's [1960-1969] (Box 23)
  - NY Academy Sci. Conference 1956: Techniques for the Study of Behavioral Effects of Drugs - "Effects of Drugs on Motivation," NEM paper. (Box 23)
  - Talks - Invitations, etc. 1963 [correspondence], 1963-1965 (Box 23)
  - Sigma Xi Lecture - Oct. 20, 1965 ["Experiments on Hunger and Thirst"] (Box 24)
  - First Talk at Rockefeller University, 1966 (Box 24)
  - Moscow Talk, 1966 - French version - "Experiments Relevant to Learning Theory and Psychopathology" (Box 24)
  - Talk at WHO [World Health Organization], 1967 (Box 24)
  - IBRO - Symposium on Brain Research and Human Behavior, Mar. 11-16, 1968 (Box 24)
  - Sigma Xi - 1968 Lecture Tour (Box 24)
  - "Brain to Behavior" - Invited Lecture at XII Inter-american Congress of Psychology, Uruguay, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Miller - American Philosoph. 1971 [NEM talk at American Philosoph. Society meeting on visceral learning] (Box 24)
  - Las Vegas Talk Outline 1/72, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Learnng and Psychotherapy Talk - Kyoto, 8/72, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Critical Periods Talk - to Fullbright [Students], NYU, 1972 (Box 24)
  - EEG Talk 1972 (Box 24)
  - Talk at St. Lawrence U., 9/26/73, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Sacred Heart (Popular Talk) 1973 (Box 24)
  - St. Lawrence College/University of Chicago Spencer Lecture, 11/6/73, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Bell Lab Talk 12/73, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Speculations on Good and Evil [NH Unitarian Church talk], 12/73, 1973 (Box 24)
  - Visceral Learning and Stress talk, '74, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Mayo Clinic talk, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Mexican Symposium talk, 1974 (Box 24)
  - APA Master Lecture, 1974 (Box 24)
  - American Association For the Advancement of Science talk, 1/27/75, 1975 (Box 24)
  - NHLI Keynote, 5/12/75, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Talk on Biofeedback and Learning Theory [1973; Budapest, 1975; London, 1975; Academy of Neuroscience, 1975; Biofeedback Research Society, 1976; Johns Hopkins, 1976; Norristown, 1976; Brown University, 1976; Association Ab. Beh., 1967] (Box 24)
  - Japan lectures, 1976 (Box 24)
  - University of TX-Arlington [Symposium on Clinical Applications of Biofeedback Techniques] 3/28/77, 1977 (Box 24)
  - Columbia School of Physicians and Surgeons, 2/5/75/Yale '77/NY Medical College, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Pre-Australia Talk Outline, 1976-1978 (Box 24)
  - "Behavioral Medicine: Stress and Biofeedback" - Talk at Biofeedback Society meeting, New Mexico, 1978 (Box 24)
  - Outline for Talks - Australia, 1978 (Box 24)
  - Talks 1978-1980 (Box 24)
  - ABMR Presidential Address, 1979 [Became NEM article #204, 1981] (Box 24)
  - Berlyne Lecture, Toronto 12/80, 1980 (Box 24)
  - Wesner Seminars, 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - APA Talk [on behavioral medicine]1981 (Box 24)
  - Miami Talk, Feb. 1981 [on biofeedback] (Box 24)
  - Talk on Behavioral Medicine and Symbiosis, Munich, 8/81, 1981 (Box 24)
  - APA 1983 (Anaheim) - Talk on Value and Ethics of Research on Animals (Box 24)
  - Behavior Therapy talk, Biofeedback Society, 1984 (Box 24)
  - "How the Brain Affects the Health of the Body" [FL and New Mexico talks], 1984 (Box 24)
  - "Value of Behavioral Research on Animals" - Presented in APA meeting, Toronto, and pub. in American Psychologist, 1984 (Box 24)
  - American Association For the Advancement of Science annual meeting, NYC, 5/27/84 - Talk on Biofeedback and Behavioral Medicine, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Talk on "Two Faces of Fear" - University of AL, 6/15/89, 1989 (Box 24)
  - Talk on "Some Trends from History to Future of Behavioral Medicine", 1991 (Box 24)
  - Talk on "How the Brain Affects the Health...", University of MD, June '92, 1992 (Box 24)
  - Talk at AAPB Meeting on future of biofeedback - [When NEM received first Distinguished Research Award, presented by Dr. Taub - See Biofeedback newsmagazine, Summer 1995] (Box 24)
  - NEM talk at Yale Clinical Lunch - "Fear as a Learned Drive" - 1996 (Box 24)
  - Talk - "Education for Learning as a Way of Life" (Box 24)
  - A-J, Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 24)
  - K-Z Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence re Animals, 1986-1989 (Box 25)
  - Prof. Nicolov (Bulgaria) re Symposium in Crete, 1984 (Box 25)
  - [Prof. Sudakov (USSR) re] Anokhin Seminar, 1986 (Box 25)
  - CIANS Symposium in Philadelphia [IV World Congress], 1985 (Box 25)
  - Eur. Association for Behavioral Therapy, meeting in Munich, 1985 (Box 25)
  - NY Academy of Sciences mtg. - NEM Talk, 5/13/85, 1985 (Box 25)
  - Rutgers 5/23/85 - D.Sc. [NEM received Dr. of Science degree], 1985 (Box 25)
  - American Association For the Advancement of Science Seminar for Teachers, 12/6/84, 1984 (Box 25)
  - AABT 11/2/84 [NEM Talk on Behavior Therapy], 1984 (Box 25)
  - Brudny Symposium, Boston, 10/21/84 [Talk on Biofeedback Training], 1984 (Box 25)
  - APA '84 - 8/24-28 [Talk on animal research], 1984 (Box 25)
  - Moscow 6/84 - Pavlovian Society, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Hofstra 11/30/83 [NEM talk "A Perspective on Behavioral Medicine"], 1983 (Box 25)
  - Memphis, 10/83 [NEM talk :"A Perspective on Behavioral Medicine"], 1983 (Box 25)
  - APA '83 [Correspondence re NEM's receiving APA Award for Distinguished Contributions to Knowledge, 1983 (Box 25)
  - WPA [Western Psychological Association], 4/27-30/83 - Invited talk on "Behavioral Medicine: Symbiosis between Laboratory and Clinic", 1983 (Box 25)
  - NIH Seminar on Anxiety, 9/83, 1983 (Box 25)
  - Purdue, Keynote Speech [for dedication of new psychology building] 3/19/82 (Box 25)
  - Sudakov Seminar 10/82 [correspondence re Hypertension Symposium, Oct. '82], 1982 (Box 25)
  - British Psychological Society 4/1-5/82 - [Talk on recent developments in behavioral medicine], 1981 (Box 25)